<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Science on ekunazanu</title>
    <link>http://ekunazanu.dev/categories/computer-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computer Science on ekunazanu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-in</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 03:22:19 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ekunazanu.dev/categories/computer-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Encryption</title>
      <link>http://ekunazanu.dev/blog/asymmetric-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 03:22:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ekunazanu.dev/blog/asymmetric-encryption/</guid>
      <description>Terminology Terms might sound very , but it is quite simple. Cryptography refers to &amp;hellip; . While the asymmetric in this context refers to their being two different keys being used to encrypt and decrypt the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast Fourier Transform</title>
      <link>http://ekunazanu.dev/blog/fast-fourier-transform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 03:22:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ekunazanu.dev/blog/fast-fourier-transform/</guid>
      <description>Note This article assumes you have a basic understanding of Fourier Transforms and Discrete Fourier Transforms. While Dicrete Fourier transforms
Including Efficiency In computer science, we use a term called Time Complexity to represent how an algorithm scales, with regards to the time needed to perform the computation, with respect to the size of the given input data. By removing the redundant calculations in FFT, we reduce the number of operations need to perform from the square of the number of the inputs to just .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fourier Transform</title>
      <link>http://ekunazanu.dev/blog/fourier-transform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:01:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ekunazanu.dev/blog/fourier-transform/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you are given a function $y = f(x)$. Now what if I asked you to to represent this function as a sum of sine waves? Seems tricky, if not impossible at first. It might look daunting from afar, but the underlying principle behind Fourier transforms is actually relatively simple and really elegant.
Time v Frequency A time domain vs a frequency domain graph of the same signal Use Cases Sound Processing Euler&amp;rsquo;s Formula The complex plane for any number, $x^{yi}$ results in a comlex number $a + bi$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test</title>
      <link>http://ekunazanu.dev/blog/testtemplate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:01:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ekunazanu.dev/blog/testtemplate/</guid>
      <description>Hidden note This is an example collapsed note Open note This is an example open note Paragraph with inline math $f(x) = x^{2}$ $y_t = beta_0 + theta_1 x_t + epsilon_t$ $$e\equiv \lim_{n\to\infty} \biggl( 1 + \frac{1}{n} \biggr)^n = 2.71828$$
Header2 Paragraph with a link
Some caption Header3 Another paragraph with emphasis or strong emphasis. monospaced string or inline code. Underline is not supported and discouraged, to reduce confusion with links.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
